A Guide to the J. George Harrar Papers FA046
Rockefeller Archive Center
J. George Harrar papers
1906-1982, bulk 1958-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harrar, J. George (Jacob George)
Rockefeller Foundation
FA046
18.31 Cubic Feet 47 document cases, 1 oversize
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
The J. George Harrar Papers are divided into four series:
Series 1 - Correspondence Series 2 - Speeches, Manuscripts and Publications Series 3 - MiscellanySeries 1019 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
Jacob George Harrar was born in Painesville, Ohio, on December 2, 1906, to Ellwood Harrar, an engineer, and Lucetta Sternes Harrar. He attended Oberlin College from 1924 to 1928 where he majored in biology and excelled in athletics. After receiving the A.B. degree from Oberlin, Harrar continued his education at the Iowa State College of Agriculture and Mechanical Arts. He was awarded the M.S. degree in 1929 and immediately embarked on a career in teaching and agricultural research as an assistant professor at the College of Agriculture, University of Puerto Rico. Within a year Harrar became head of the department of biology. He left that position in 1934 to pursue a Ph.D. in plant pathology at the University of Minnesota. It was here he began a close personal and professional relationship with E. C. Stakman, under whom he studied. Later, in 1958, they collaborated on the book, "Principles of Plant Pathology."
In 1935, Harrar, having achieved a doctorate degree in plant pathology, once again resumed teaching, accepting an assistant professorship at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute. Rising to full professor in 1937, Harrar remained at the Institute until 1941. From 1941 to 1942 he headed the Division of Plant Pathology and the Agricultural Experiment Station at Washington State College.
In 1942, Harrar left academics to create and administer in Mexico the Rockefeller Foundation's first cooperative assistance program in agricultural science. With his team of American specialists, Harrar implemented a Foundation program of soil and hybrid experimentation to improve wheat and corn yields. Within a few years the Mexican program proved enormously successful and the Foundation was invited to implement the same program in Colombia, Chile, and India. Harrar is generally regarded as the father of what soon became known as "The Green Revolution."
Harrar, in 1952, became Deputy Director for Agriculture, Division of Natural Sciences and Agriculture, of the Rockefeller Foundation. In 1955, he became Director for Agriculture organizing further projects in agricultural assistance and cooperation in all the Central American countries. He was appointed Vice President of the Foundation in 1959, and in 1961 succeeded Dean Rusk as its President. Under Harrar, the Rockefeller Foundation during the 1960s reoriented its programs to concentrate in five areas: the conquest of hunger, by improving the quantity and quality of food supplies; the solution of population problems; the strengthening of emerging centers of learning in developing nations; the provision of better educational opportunities for the disadvantaged groups in the U. S.; and the enhancement of the cultural lives of Americans.
Retiring in 1972, Harrar was the first man ever to be appointed a Life Fellow of the Rockefeller Foundation. During the 1970s he continued his involvement as a member of such professional and scientific organizations as the National Academy of Sciences and the Nutrition Foundation. In 1980 he was awarded the Aztec Eagle Award, the highest honor bestowed by the Mexican government for service to their country by a foreign citizen. He also, during his lifetime, received numerous honors, degrees, and citations from many other foreign governments and from both American and foreign universities.
In addition to "Strategy for the Conquest of Hunger, Selected Papers of J. George Harrar," he was the author of numerous scientific research papers in the fields of phytopathology and mycology, and many articles of general interest on world food problems, population, private philanthropy, economic development overseas, and environmental quality.
J. George Harrar died on April 18, 1982.
Scope and Contents note
The J. George Harrar Papers mainly consist of material relating to Harrar's various activities outside The Rockefeller Foundation between 1958 and 1982. The bulk of the collection is made up of correspondence, but it also contains publications, speeches, clippings, awards, interviews, photographs, and books.
The collection strongly reflects Harrar's pre-eminence as a world agricultural expert. This is illustrated in his correspondence with organizations such as the Academy of Natural Sciences, the Agribusiness Council, the International Development Service, the Institute of Nutrition Sciences, the National Academy of Sciences, the Nutrition Foundation, and the Cotton Research and Development Program. A related interest in population is represented in correspondence with the Dreyfus Third Century Fund, Projects for Population Action, and in letters to and from William Draper.
Harrar's views on foundations and private philanthropy are illustrated in his correspondence with the Council on Foundations, the Foundation Center, the Foundation Executives Group, and in material relating to the Patman Investigation and other House or Senate Committees before which Harrar appeared. Correspondence of a more personal nature can be found within the first three subseries: Outgoing, Confidential, and General.
Very few of Harrar's scientific writings are represented in the collection. Most of the written material relates to subjects that concerned him later in his career, such as world hunger, food production, and private philanthropy.
Material illustrating Harrar's thirty years (1942-1972) with the Rockefeller Foundation is contained within the Rockefeller Foundation Archives.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2A 26
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Mrs. Georgetta Harrar donated the papers of J. George Harrar to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 1982.
Agriculture -- Research; Population; Agriculture; Food production and natural resources; Philanthropy; Hunger
- Correspondence, 1946-1982; 1; 12.1 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is divided into five subseries:
  Subseries 1 - OutgoingSubseries 2 - ConfidentialSubseries 3 - GeneralSubseries 4 - Collateral InterestsSubseries 5 - Correspondence Relating to Written Material (in Series 2)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing, 1968-1982; 1_1
    Arrangement note
    This subseries is arranged chronologically, and thereunder alphabetically.
    Scope and Contents note
    This subseries consists of Harrar's chronological file of outgoing correspondence. Correspondents for each year appear in alphabetical order. These letters are dispersed among a great number of correspondents that include Ralph Bunch, Howard Baker, Jr., John K. Galbraith, Norman Borlaug, Bill Moyers, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Dean Rusk, E. J. Wellhausen, as well as letters to several Latin American and Asian leaders.
    - A-C, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - D-G, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - H-L, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - M-P, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - R-S, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - T-Z, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A-B, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - C-F, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - G-I, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - J-M, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - N-R, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - S-T, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - U-Z, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - A-C, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - D-H, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - I-M, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - N-R, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - S-Z, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - A-E, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - F-M, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - N-Y, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - A-Z, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - A-Z, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - A-J, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - K-R, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - S-Z, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - A-K, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - L-Z, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - A-L, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - M-Z, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - A-Z, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - A-Z, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - A-Z, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - A-E, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - F-O, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - P-Z, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - A-H, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - I-Q, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - R-Z, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - Confidential, 1954-1982; 1_2
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    This subseries consists of correspondence that was originally contained within files designated as "Confidential" or "Personal." The letters concern a number of topics.
    - 1954-1960 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - 1961 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - 1962 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - 1963 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - 1964 (January-June) (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - 1964 (July-December) (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - 1965 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - 1966 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - 1967 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - 1968 (January-June) (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - 1968 (July-December) (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - 1970 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - 1971 (January-May) (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - 1971 (June-December) (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - 1972 (January-June) (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - 1972 (July-December) (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - 1974 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - 1976, 1978 (January-June) (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - 1978 (July-December) (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence - General, 1961-1982; 1_3
    This subseries consists of correspondence originally contained within files designated as "General." Included are letters of congratulations concerning Harrar's appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, letters observing his retirement in 1972, and letters relating to his trip to China in 1973. Other, miscellaneous correspondence, is also included.
    - Letters of Congratulation, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Letters of Congratulation, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Telegrams, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Responses, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Responses, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - 1946-1971 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - 1972 (January-August) (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - 1972 (September-December) (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Retirement Letters, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - 1973 (January-May) (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - 1973 (June-August) (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - 1973 (September-December) (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - 1974 (January-April) (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - 1974 (May-July) (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - 1974 (August-September) (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - 1974 (October-December) (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - 1975 (January-February) (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - 1975 (March-July) (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - 1975 (August-December) (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - 1976 - 1978 (May) (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - May 1978 - February 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - 1979 (March-December) (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - 1980 (January-August) (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - 1980 (September-December) (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - 1981 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - 1982 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - Correspondence - Collateral Interests, 1960-1982; 1_4
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject (e.g. Academy of Natural Sciences, Academia Nazionale di Agricoltura, Advisory Committee on ...).
    This subseries, the largest, preserves Harrar's subject files pertaining to the corporations, clubs, professional associations, scientific societies, government committees, and other organizations Harrar was involved with either as a member, trustee, or advisor.
    - The Academy of Natural Sciences, 1974-1976, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 89)
    - Academia Nazionale di Agricultura, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 90)
    - Advisory Committee on the Application of Science and Technology, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 91)
    - Advisory Committee on Private Enterprise in Foreign Aid, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - Africa (National Academy of Sciences (NAS)), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    - Africa (National Academy of Sciences (NAS)), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 94)
    - Africa (National Academy of Sciences (NAS)), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 95)
    - Africa (National Academy of Sciences (NAS)), 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 96)
    - The Agribusiness Council, Inc., 1974 (Box 13, Folder 97)
    - The Agribusiness Council, Inc., 1974 (Box 14, Folder 98)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 99)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - The Americas Foundation, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - American Phytopathological Society - Award, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 103)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1962-1982 (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - The Atlantic Council, 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 105)
    - Aztec Eagle Award, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - Boyce Thompson Institute, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Boys Club of America, 1964-1972 (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - Campbell Soup, 1962-1982 (Box 15, Folder 109)
    - Century Association, 1961-1973 (Box 15, Folder 110)
    - Century Association, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT), 1972-1977 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - Citizen's Commission for International Development, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Citizen's Commission of Science, Law and Food Supply, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - The City Prize of New York, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 115)
    - Columbia University - Presbyterian Hospital, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 116)
    - Columbia University - Presbyterian Hospital, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 117)
    - Commission on Critical Choices, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 118)
    - Commission on Critical Choices, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - Commission on U.S.-Latin American Relations, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - Commission on U.S.-Latin American Relations, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 121)
    - Compania Financiera Dominicana, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 122)
    - Committee on International Centers, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 123)
    - Conference on Human Environment - Stockholm, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 124)
    - Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 125)
    - Cornell University - A. D. White Professorship, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 126)
    - Cosmos Club, 1955-1972 (Box 17, Folder 127)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1961-1977 (Box 17, Folder 128)
    - Council on Foundations, 1966-1970 (Box 17, Folder 129)
    - Cotton Development International, 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 130)
    - Cotton Research and Development, 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 131)
    - Cotton Research and Development, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 132)
    - Development and Resource Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 133)
    - Dreyfus Third Century Fund, 1980-1982 (Box 18, Folder 134)
    - Eliot Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 135)
    - Edna McConnel Clark Foundation, 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 136)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica - Science Yearbook, 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 137)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica - Science Yearbook, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 138)
    - Escuela Agricola Pan Americana, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 139)
    - The Foundation Center, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 140)
    - The Foundation Center, 1972-1975 (Box 18, Folder 141)
    - Foundation Executives Group, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 142)
    - Foundation Executives Group, May-August 1965 (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Foundation Executives Group, September-December 1965 (Box 19, Folder 144)
    - Foundation Executives Group, January-April 1966 (Box 19, Folder 145)
    - Foundation Executives Group, April-June 1966 (Box 19, Folder 146)
    - Foundation Executives Group, July-December 1966 (Box 19, Folder 147)
    - Foundation Executives Group, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 148)
    - Foundation Executives Group, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 149)
    - Foundation Executives Group, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 150)
    - Foundation Executives Group, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 151)
    - General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, April-May 1965 (Box 20, Folder 152)
      Related Materials
      See also the files for President's General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs (Boxes 32-33, Folders 239-250).
    - General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, June-October 1965 (Box 20, Folder 153)
    - General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, February-July 1966 (Box 20, Folder 154)
    - General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, August-October 1966 (Box 21, Folder 155)
    - General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, November-December 1966 (Box 21, Folder 156)
    - Harvard University - Visiting Committee on the Harvard Medical School and School of Dental Medicine, 1967-1972 (Box 21, Folder 157)
    - Harvard University - Visiting Committee to Department of Biology, 1957-1963 (Box 21, Folder 158)
    - Hearings Before House Committee on Agriculture, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 159)
    - House Ways and Means Committee, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 160)
    - House Ways and Means Committee, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 161)
    - House Ways and Means Committee, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 162)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 163)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 164)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, April-September 1980 (Box 22, Folder 165)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, October-December 1980 (Box 22, Folder 166)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, January-May 1981 (Box 22, Folder 167)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, June-September 1981 (Box 22, Folder 168)
    - International Agricultural Development Service, October 1981-April 1982 (Box 22, Folder 169)
    - International Council for Educational Development, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 170)
    - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 171)
    - International Finance Sub-Committee, August 29, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 172)
    - International Flavors and Fragrances, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 173)
    - International Flavors and Fragrances, 1973-1975 (Box 23, Folder 175)
    - International Flavors and Fragrances, 1976-1980 (Box 23, Folder 176)
    - International Flavors and Fragrances, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 177)
    - International Flavors and Fragrances, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 178)
    - Institute of Nutrition Sciences, 1964-1970 (Box 24, Folder 179)
    - The International Rice Research Institute, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 180)
    - Lefkowitz Hearings - New York State, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 181)
    - Mayor's Science and Technology Advisory Council, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 182)
    - Mayor's Science and Technology Advisory Council, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 183)
    - Merck, 1976-1982 (Box 24, Folder 184)
    - Mexican Agricultural Program - Proposed Book, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 185)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Visiting Committee, 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 186)
    - Monell Chemical Senses Fund, 1968-1975 (Box 24, Folder 187)
    - Monell Chemical Senses Fund, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 188)
    - Monell Chemical Senses Fund, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 189)
    - Monell Chemical Senses Fund, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 190)
    - Monell Chemical Senses Fund, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 191)
    - Monell Chemical Senses Fund, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 192)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1966-1972 (Box 25, Folder 193)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1973-1980 (Box 26, Folder 194)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Committee on Creation of a Tropical Research Foundation, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 195)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Committee on Creation of a Tropical Research Foundation, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 196)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Committee on Inter-American Scientific Cooperation, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 197)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Committee on Inter-American Scientific Cooperation, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 198)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Committee on Inter-American Scientific Cooperation, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 199)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - Latin American Committee, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 200)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - U. S. Committee of the International Union of Biological Sciences, 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 201)
    - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) - University of the West Indies, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 202)
    - National Institute of Health - International Centers, 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 203)
    - National Institute of Health - International Centers, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 204)
    - Natural Resources Conference (National Acadmey of Sciences (NAS)), 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 205)
    - Natural Resources Conference (National Acadmey of Sciences (NAS)), 1962 (Box 27, Folder 206)
    - National Urban League, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 207)
    - National Science Foundation, 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 208)
    - National Science Foundation, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 209)
    - Near East Foundation, 1973-1980 (Box 28, Folder 210)
    - Nebraska Symposium - "The Physiological Aspects of Crop Yield", 1969 (Box 28, Folder 211)
    - New Perspective Fund, 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 212)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 213)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 214)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 215)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 216)
    - Nutrition Foundation, January-September 1969 (Box 29, Folder 217)
    - Nutrition Foundation, October-December 1969 (Box 29, Folder 218)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 219)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1971-1975 (Box 29, Folder 220)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1976-1980 (Box 29, Folder 221)
    - Nutrition Foundation, 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 222)
    - Nutrition Foundation - Citizen Case, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 223)
    - U. S. Senate - Select Committee on Nutrition and Human Needs, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 224)
    - Overseas Development Council, 1973-1977 (Box 30, Folder 225)
    - Oberlin College, 1961-1968 (Box 30, Folder 226)
    - Oberlin College, January-February 1970 (Box 30, Folder 227)
    - Oberlin College, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 228)
    - Patman Investigation, January-June 1962 (Box 30, Folder 229)
    - Patman Investigation, July-November 1962 (Box 30, Folder 230)
    - Patman Investigation, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 231)
    - Patman Investigation, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 232)
    - Patman Investigation, 1965-1969 (Box 31, Folder 233)
    - Pilgrims of the United States, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 234)
    - Population Crisis Committee, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 235)
    - Population Crisis Committee, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 236)
    - Population Crisis Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 237)
    - Population Crisis Committee, 1975-1982 (Box 31, Folder 238)
    - President's General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, 1960-1966 (Box 32, Folder 239)
      See also the files for the General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs (Boxes 20-21, Folders 152-156).
    - President's General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, August 1966 (Box 32, Folder 240)